<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<resources>
	<!--  These quests do not need translation: -->
	<string name="questlist_nondisplayed">
[id|name|showInLog|stages[progress|logText|rewardExperience|finishesQuest|]|];
{nondisplay|Placeholder for hidden quest stages (not displayed)|0|{
	{10|Tavern room in Foaming Flask|||}
	{16|Sleeping quarters in Blackwater mountain|||}
	{17|Sleeping quarters in Crossroads1|||}
	{18|Shopping from Minarra in Crossroads tower|||}
	{19|Sleeping quarters in Loneford10|||}
	{20|Selling Izthiel claws to Gauward|||}
	}|};
{crossglen|TODO|0|{{1|||0|}}|};
{fallhaventavern|Room to rent|0|{{10|||1|}}|};
{arcir|Elythara|0|{{10|||0|}}|};
	</string>

	<string name="questlist">
[id|name|showInLog|stages[progress|logText|rewardExperience|finishesQuest|]|];
{andor|Search for Andor|1|{
	{1|My father Mikhail says that Andor has not been home since yesterday. I should go look for him in the village.||0|}
	{10|Leonid tells me that he saw Andor talking to Gruil. I should go ask Gruil if he knows more.||0|}
	{20|Gruil wants me to bring him a poison gland. Then he might talk more. He tells me that some poisonous snakes have such a gland.||0|}
	{30|Gruil tells me that Andor was looking for someone called Umar. I should go ask his friend Gaela in Fallhaven to the east.||0|}
	{40|I talked to Gaela in Fallhaven. He tells me to go see Bucus and ask about the thieves guild.||0|}
	{50|Bucus has allowed me to enter the hatch in the derelict house in Fallhaven. I should go talk to Umar.||0|}
	{51|Umar in the Fallhaven thieves guild recognized me, but must have me mixed up with Andor. Apparently, Andor has been to see him.||0|}
	{55|Umar told me that Andor went to see a potion maker called Lodar. I should search for his hideaway.||0|}
	{61|I heard a story in Loneford, where it seemed like Andor had been in Loneford, and that he might have had something to do with the illness that the people are suffering from there. I am not sure if it actually was Andor. If it was Andor, why would he have made the people of Loneford ill?||0|}
	}|};
{mikhail_bread|Breakfast bread|1|{
	{100|I have brought the bread to Mikhail.||1|}
	{10|Mikhail wants me to go buy a loaf of bread from Mara at the town hall.||0|}
	}|};
{mikhail_rats|Rats!|1|{
	{100|I have killed the two rats in our garden.|20|1|}
	{10|Mikhail wants me to go check our garden for some rats. I should kill the rats in our garden and return to Mikhail. If I get hurt, I can come back to the bed and rest to regain my health.||0|}
	}|};
{leta|Missing husband|1|{
	{10|Leta in Crossglen village wants me to look for her husband Oromir.||0|}
	{20|I have found Oromir in Crossglen village, hiding from his wife Leta.||0|}
	{100|I have told Leta that Oromir is hiding in Crossglen village.|30|1|}
	}|};
{odair|Rat infestation|1|{
	{10|Odair wants me to clear the supply cave in Crossglen village of rats. In particular, I should kill the large rat and return to Odair.||0|}
	{100|I have helped Odair clear out the rats in the supply cave in Crossglen village.|30|1|}
	}|};
{bonemeal|Disallowed substance|1|{
	{10|Leonid in Crossglen town hall tells me that there was a disturbance in the village some weeks ago. Apparently, Lord Geomyr has banned all use of bonemeal as a healing substance.\n\nTharal, the town priest should know more.||0|}
	{20|Tharal does not want to talk about bonemeal. I might be able to persuade him by bringing him 5 insect wings.||0|}
	{30|Tharal tells me that bonemeal is a very potent healing substance, and is quite upset that it is not allowed anymore. I should go see Thoronir in Fallhaven if I want to learn more. I should tell him the password \'Glow of the Shadow\'.||0|}
	{40|I have talked to Thoronir in Fallhaven. He might be able to mix me a bonemeal potion if I bring him 5 skeletal bones. There should be some skeletons in an abandoned house north of Fallhaven.||0|}
	{100|I have brought the bones to Thoronir. He is now able to supply me with bonemeal potions.\nI should be careful when using them though, since Lord Geomyr has banned their use.|90|1|}
	}|};
{jan|Fallen friends|1|{
	{10|Jan tells me his story, where he and his two friends Gandir and Irogotu, went down the hole to dig for a hidden treasure, but they started fighting and Irogotu killed Gandir in his rage.\nI should bring back Gandir\'s ring from Irogotu, and see Jan when I have it.||0|}
	{100|Irogotu is dead. I have brought Jan the ring of Gandir, and avenged his friend.|150|1|}
	}|};
{bucus|Key of Luthor|1|{
	{10|Bucus in Fallhaven might know something about Andor. He wants me to bring him the key of Luthor from the catacombs beneath Fallhaven church.||0|}
	{20|The catacombs beneath Fallhaven church are closed off. Athamyr is the only one with both permission and the bravery to enter them. I should go see him in his house southwest of the church.||0|}
	{30|Athamyr wants me to bring him some cooked meat, then maybe he will want to talk more.||0|}
	{40|I brought some cooked meat to Athamyr.|70|0|}
	{50|Athamyr has given me permission to enter the catacombs beneath Fallhaven church.||0|}
	{100|I brought Bucus the key of Luthor.|215|1|}
	}|};
{fallhavendrunk|Drunken tale|1|{
	{10|A drunk outside Fallhaven tavern began telling me his story, but wants me to bring him some mead. I don\'t know if his story will lead anywhere though.||0|}
	{100|The drunk told me he used to travel with Unnmir. I should go talk to Unnmir.||1|}
	}|};
{calomyran|Calomyran secrets|1|{
	{10|An old man standing outside in Fallhaven has lost his book \'Calomyran Secrets\'. I should go look for it. Maybe in Arcir\'s house to the south?||0|}
	{20|I found a torn page of a book called \'Calomyran Secrets\' with the name \'Larcal\' written on it.||0|}
	{100|I gave the book back to the old man.|60|1|}
	}|};
{nocmar|Lost treasures|1|{
	{10|Unnmir told me he used to be an adventurer, and gave me a hint to go see Nocmar. His house is just southwest of the tavern in Fallhaven.||0|}
	{20|Nocmar tells me he used to be a smith. But Lord Geomyr has banned the use of heartsteel, so he cannot forge his weapons anymore.\nIf I can find a heartstone and bring it to Nocmar, he should be able to forge the heartsteel again.||0|}
	{200|I have brought a heartstone to Nocmar. He should have heartsteel items available now.|120|1|}
	}|};
{flagstone|Ancient secrets|1|{
	{10|I met a guard on sentry outside a fortress called Flagstone. The guard told me that Flagstone used to be a prison camp for runaway workers from Mount Galmore. Recently, there has been an increase in undead monsters pouring out from Flagstone. I should investigate the source of the undead monsters. The guard tells me to return to him if I need help.||0|}
	{20|I found a dug out tunnel beneath Flagstone, that seems to lead to a larger cave. The cave is guarded by a demon that I am not even able to approach. Maybe the guard outside Flagstone knows more?||0|}
	{30|The guard tells me that the former warden used to have a necklace that he always wore. The necklace probably has the words required to approach the demon. I should return to the guard to decipher any message on the necklace once I have found it.||0|}
	{31|I found the former warden of Flagstone on the upper level. I should return to the guard now.||0|}
	{40|I have learned the words required to approach the demon beneath Flagstone. \'Daylight Shadow\'.|160|0|}
	{50|Deep beneath Flagstone, I found the source of the undead infestation. A creature born from the grief of the former prisoners of Flagstone.||0|}
	{60|I found one prisoner, Narael, alive deep beneath Flagstone. Narael was once a citizen of Nor City. He is too weak to walk by himself, but if I can find his wife in Nor City, I would be handsomely rewarded.|210|1|}
	}|};
{vacor|Missing pieces|1|{
	{10|A mage called Vacor in southwest Fallhaven has been trying to cast a rift spell.\nThere was something not right about him, he seemed very obsessed with his spell. Something about him gaining a power from it.||0|}
	{20|Vacor wants me to bring him the four pieces of the rift spell that he claims was stolen from him. The four bandits should be somewhere south of Fallhaven.||0|}
	{30|I have brought the four pieces of the rift spell to Vacor.|120|0|}
	{40|Vacor tells me about his former apprentice Unzel, who had started to question Vacor. Vacor now wants me to kill Unzel. I should be able to find him to the southwest outside of Fallhaven. I should bring his signet ring to Vacor once I have killed him.||0|}
	{50|Unzel gives me a choice to side with either Vacor or him.||0|}
	{51|I have chosen to side with Unzel. I should go to southwest Fallhaven to talk to Vacor about Unzel and the Shadow.||0|}
	{53|I started a fight with Unzel. I should bring his ring to Vacor once he is dead.||0|}
	{54|I started a fight with Vacor. I should bring his ring to Unzel once he is dead.||0|}
	{60|I have killed Unzel and told Vacor about the deed.|160|1|}
	{61|I have killed Vacor and told Unzel about the deed.|160|1|}
	}|};
</string>

	<string name="questlist_v068">
[id|name|showInLog|stages[progress|logText|rewardExperience|finishesQuest|]|];
{farrik|Night visit|1|{
	{10|Farrik in the Fallhaven thieves guild told me of a plan to help a fellow thief escape from Fallhaven prison.||0|}
	{20|Farrik in the Fallhaven thieves guild told me the details of the plan, and I accepted to help him. The guard captain apparently has a drinking problem. The plan is that I get a prepared mead from the cook in the thieves guild that will knock out the guard captain in the prison. I might be required to bribe the guard captain.||0|}
	{25|I got the prepared mead from the cook in the thieves guild.||0|}
	{30|I told Farrik that I don\'t fully agree with their plan. I might tell the guard captain about their shady plan.||0|}
	{32|I have given the prepared mead to the guard captain.||0|}
	{40|I have told the guard captain of the plan that the thieves have to release their friend.||0|}
	{50|The guard captain wants me to tell the thieves that the security will be lowered for tonight. We might be able to catch some of the thieves.||0|}
	{60|I managed to bribe the guard captain into drinking the prepared mead. He should be out during the night allowing the thieves to break their friend free.||0|}
	{70|Farrik rewarded me for helping the thieves guild.|150|1|}
	{80|I have told Farrik that the security will be lowered tonight.||0|}
	{90|The guard captain thanked me for helping him plan to catch the thieves. He said he will also tell other guards that I helped him.|170|1|}
	}|};
{lodar|A lost potion|1|{
	{10|I should find a potion maker called Lodar. Umar in Fallhaven thieves guild told me I that I will need to know the right words to pass a guardian in order to reach Lodar\'s hideaway.||0|}
	{15|Umar told me I should go see someone galled Ogam in Vilegard. Ogam can supply me with the right words to reach Lodar\'s hideaway.||0|}
	{20|I have visited Ogam in southwest Vilegard. He was talking in what seemed like riddles. I could barely make out some details when I asked about Lodar\'s hideaway. \'Halfway between the Shadow and the light. Rocky formations.\' and the words \'Glow of the Shadow.\' were among the things he said. I am not sure what they mean.||0|}
	}|};
{vilegard|Trusting an outsider|1|{
	{10|The people of Vilegard are very suspicious of outsiders. I was told to go see Jolnor in the Vilegard chapel if I want to gain their trust.||0|}
	{20|I have talked to Jolnor in the Vilegard chapel. He suggests I help three influential people in order to gain the trust of the people in Vilegard. I should help Kaori, Wrye and Jolnor in Vilegard.||0|}
	{30|I have helped all three people in Vilegard that Jolnor suggested. Now the people of Vilegard should trust me more.|210|1|}
	}|};
{kaori|Kaori\'s errands|1|{
	{5|Jolnor in Vilegard chapel wants me to talk to Kaori in northern Vilegard, to see if she wants any help.||0|}
	{10|Kaori in northern Vilegard wants me to bring her 10 bonemeal potions.||0|}
	{20|I have brought 10 bonemeal potions to Kaori.|52|1|}
	}|};
{wrye|Uncertain cause|1|{
	{10|Jolnor in Vilegard chapel wants me to talk to Wrye in northern Vilegard. She has apparently lost her son recently.||0|}
	{20|Wrye in northern Vilegard tells me that her son Rincel has gone missing. She thinks that he has died or gotten critically hurt.||0|}
	{30|Wrye tells me that she thinks the royal guard from Feygard are involved in his disappearance, and that they have recruited him.||0|}
	{40|Wrye wants me to go search for clues as to what has happened to her son.||0|}
	{41|I should go look in the Vilegard tavern and the Foaming Flask tavern north of Vilegard.|20|0|}
	{42|I heard of a boy being in the Foaming Flask tavern a while ago. Apparently he left to the west of the tavern somewhere.||0|}
	{80|To the northwest of Vilegard I found a man that had found Rincel fighting some monsters. Rincel had apparently left Vilegard by his own will to go see the city of Feygard. I should go tell Wrye in northern Vilegard what happened to her son.||0|}
	{90|I have told Wrye the truth about her son\'s disappearance.|52|1|}
	}|};
{jolnor|Spies in the foam|1|{
	{10|Jolnor in Vilegard chapel tells me of a guard outside of the Foaming Flask tavern, that he thinks is a spy for the Feygard royal guard. He wants me to make the guard disappear, in any way that I see fit. The tavern should be just north of Vilegard.||0|}
	{20|I have convinced the guard outside the Foaming Flask tavern to leave after his shift ends.||0|}
	{21|I have started a fight with the guard outside the Foaming Flask tavern. I should bring his Feygard royal guard ring to Jolnor once he is dead to show Jolnor that he has disappeared.||0|}
	{30|I have told Jolnor that the guard is now gone.|63|1|}
	}|};
	</string>

	<string name="questlist_v069">
[id|name|showInLog|stages[progress|logText|rewardExperience|finishesQuest|]|];
{bwm_agent|The agent and the beast|1|{
	{1|I met a man seeking help for his settlement, the \'Blackwater Mountain\'. Supposedly, his settlement is being attacked by monsters and bandits, and they need help from the outside.|||}
	{5|I have agreed to help the man and Blackwater Mountain in dealing with the problem.|||}
	{10|The man told me to meet him on the other side of the collapsed mine. He will crawl through the mine shaft and I will descend into the pitch-black abandoned mine.|||}
	{20|I have navigated through the pitch-black abandoned mine, and met the man on the other side. He seemed very anxious about telling me to head straight to the east once I exit the mine. I should meet the man at the bottom of the mountain to the east.|||}
	{25|I heard a story about Prim and the Blackwater Mountain settlement fighting against each other.|||}
	{30|I should follow the mountain path up the mountain to the Blackwater settlement.|||}
	{40|I met the man again on my way up to Blackwater Mountain. I should proceed further up the mountain.|||}
	{50|I have made it up to the snow-filled parts of the Blackwater Mountain. The man told me to proceed further up the mountain. Apparently, the Blackwater Mountain settlement is close by.|||}
	{60|I have reached the Blackwater mountain settlement. I should find and talk to their battle master, Harlenn.|||}
	{65|I have spoken to Harlenn in the Blackwater Mountain settlement. Apparently, the settlement is under attack by a number of monsters, the Aulaeth and white wyrms. On top of that, they are being attacked by the people of Prim.|||}
	{66|Harlenn thinks the people of Prim are behind the monster attacks somehow.|||}
	{70|Harlenn wants me to give a message to Guthbered of Prim. Either the people of Prim stop their attacks on the Blackwater Mountain settlement, or they will have to be dealt with themselves. I should go talk to Guthbered in Prim.|||}
	{80|Guthbered denies that the people of Prim have anything to do with the monster attacks on the Blackwater mountain settlement. I should go talk to Harlenn|||}
	{90|Harlenn is sure that the people of Prim are behind the attacks somehow.|||}
	{95|Harlenn wants me to go to Prim and look for signs that they are preparing for an attack on the settlement. I should go look for clues around where Guthbered stays.|||}
	{100|I have found some plans in Prim about recruiting mercenaries and attacking the Blackwater Mountain settlement. I should go talk to Harlenn immediately.|||}
	{110|Harlenn thanked me for investigating the attack plans.|115||}
	{120|To make the attacks on the Blackwater Mountain settlement stop, Harlenn wants me to assassinate Guthbered in Prim.|||}
	{130|I have started a fight with Guthbered.|||}
	{131|I told Guthbered that I was sent to kill him, but I let him live. He thanked me deeply, and left Prim.|210||}
	{149|I have told Harlenn that Guthbered is gone.|||}
	{150|Harlenn thanked me for the help I have provided. Hopefully, the attacks on the Blackwater Mountain settlement should stop now.|500||}
	{240|I am now trusted in the Blackwater Mountain settlement, and all services should be available for me to use.||1|}
	{250|I have decided to not help the people of the Blackwater Mountain settlement.||1|}
	{251|Since I am helping Prim, Harlenn no longer wants to talk to me.||1|}
	}|};
{prim_innquest|Well rested|1|{
	{10|I talked to the cook in Prim, at the base of Blackwater Mountain. There is a back room available for rent, but it is currently rented out to Arghest. I should go talk to Arghest to see whether he still wants to rent the room. The cook pointed me towards the southwest of Prim.|||}
	{20|I talked to Arghest about the back room at the inn. He is still interested in having it as an option to rest at. But he told me he could probably be persuaded to let me use it if I compensate him sufficiently.|||}
	{30|Arghest wants me to bring him 5 bottles of milk. I can probably find some milk in any of the larger villages.|||}
	{40|I have brought the milk to Arghest. He agreed to let me use the back room at the Prim inn. I should be able to rest there now. I should go talk to the cook at the inn.|50||}
	{50|I have explained to the cook that I have permission by Arghest to use the back room.||1|}
	}|};
{prim_hunt|Clouded intent|1|{
	{10|Just outside the collapsed mine on the way to Blackwater Mountain, I met a man from the village of Prim. He begged me to help them.|||}
	{11|The village of Prim needs help from someone from the outside to deal with attacks from some monsters. I should speak to Guthbered in Prim if I want to help them.|||}
	{15|Guthbered can be found in the main hall of Prim. I should look for a stone house in the center of town.|||}
	{20|I talked to Guthbered about the story about Prim. Prim has recently been under constant attack from the Blackwater Mountain settlement.|||}
	{25|Guthbered wants me to go up to the settlement atop the Blackwater Mountain and ask their battle master Harlenn why (or if) they have summoned the Gornaud monsters against Prim.|||}
	{30|I have talked to Harlenn about the attacks on Prim. He denies that the people of the Blackwater Mountain settlement have anything to do with them. I should go talk to Guthbered in Prim again.|||}
	{40|Guthbered still believes that the people in the Blackwater settlement have something to do with the attacks.|||}
	{50|Guthbered wants me to go look for any clues that the people of the Blackwater Mountain settlement is preparing for a larger attack on Prim. I should go look for hints near Harlenn\'s private quarters, but make sure not to be seen.|||}
	{60|I have found some papers around Harlenn\'s private quarters outlining a plan to attack Prim. I should go talk to Guthbered immediately.|||}
	{70|Guthbered thanked me for helping him find evidence of the plans for an attack.|115||}
	{80|In order to make the attacks on Prim stop, Guthbered wants me to kill Harlenn up in the Blackwater Mountain settlement.|||}
	{90|I have started a fight with Harlenn.|||}
	{91|I told Harlenn that I was sent to kill him, but I let him live. He thanked me deeply, and left the settlement.|210||}
	{99|I have told Guthbered that Harlenn is gone.|||}
	{100|Guthbered thanked me for the help I have provided to Prim. Hopefully, the attacks on Prim should stop now. As thanks, Guthbered gave me some items and a forged permit so that I can enter the inner chamber up in the Blackwater Mountain settlement.|500||}
	{140|I have shown the forged permit to the guard and was let through to the inner chamber.|||}
	{240|I am now trusted in Prim, and all services should be available for me to use.||1|}
	{250|I have decided to not help the people of Prim.||1|}
	{251|Since I am helping the Blackwater Mountain settlement, Guthbered no longer wants to talk to me.||1|}
	}|};
{kazaul|Lights in the dark|1|{
	{8|I have made my way into the inner chamber in the Blackwater Mountain settlement and found a group of mages led by a man named Throdna.|||}
	{9|Throdna seems very interested in someone (or something) called Kazaul, and in particular a ritual performed in its name.|||}
	{10|I have agreed to help Throdna find out more about the ritual itself, by looking for pieces of the ritual that apparently are scattered across the mountain. I should go look for the parts of the Kazaul ritual on the mountain path down from Blackwater Mountain to Prim.|||}
	{11|I need to find the two parts of the chant and the three pieces describing the ritual itself, and return to Throdna once I have found them all.|||}
	{21|I have found the first half of the chant for the Kazaul ritual.|||}
	{22|I have found the second half of the chant for the Kazaul ritual.|||}
	{25|I have found the first piece of the Kazaul ritual.|||}
	{26|I have found the second piece of the Kazaul ritual.|||}
	{27|I have found the third piece of the Kazaul ritual.|||}
	{30|Throdna thanked me for finding all the pieces of the ritual.|360||}
	{40|Throdna wants me to put an end to the Kazaul spawn uprising that has taken place near the Blackwater Mountain. There is a shrine at the base of the mountain that i should investigate closer.|||}
	{41|I have been given a vial of purifying spirit that Throdna wants me to apply to the shrine of Kazaul. I should return to Throdna when I have found and purified the shrine.|||}
	{50|In the shrine at the base of Blackwater Mountain, I met a guardian of Kazaul. By reciting the verses of the ritual chant, I was able to make the guardian attack me.|||}
	{60|I have purified the shrine of Kazaul.|320||}
	{100|I had expected some form of appreciation from Throdna for helping him learn more about the ritual and for purifying the shrine. But he seemed more occupied with rambling on about Kazaul. I could not make out anything sane from his ramblings.||1|}
	}|};
{bwm_wyrms|No weakness|1|{
	{10|Herec on the second level of the Blackwater Mountain settlement is researching the white wyrms outside the settlement. He wants me to bring him 5 white wyrm claws so that he can continue his research. Apparently, only some of the wyrms have these claws. I will have to kill some to find them.|||}
	{20|I have given the 5 white wyrm claws to Herec.|||}
	{30|Herec has finished making a potion of fatigue restoration that will be very useful when fighting against the wyrms in the future.|150|1|}
	}|};
{bjorgur_grave|Awoken from slumber|1|{
	{10|Bjorgur in Prim at the base of the Blackwater Mountain thinks that something has disturbed the grave of his parents, to the southwest of Prim, just outside the Elm mine.|||}
	{15|Bjorgur wants me to go check the grave, and make sure his family\'s dagger is still secure in the tomb.|||}
	{20|Fulus in Prim is interested in obtaining Bjorgur\'s family dagger that Bjorgur\'s grandfather used to possess.|||}
	{30|I met a man that wielded a strange looking dagger in the lower parts of a tomb to the southwest of Prim. He must have robbed this dagger from the grave.|||}
	{40|I placed the dagger back into its place in the tomb. The restless undead seem much less restless now, strangely enough.|20||}
	{50|Bjorgur thanked me for my assistance. He told me I should also seek his relatives in Feygard.|110|1|}
	{51|I have told Fulus that I helped Bjorgur return his family dagger to its original place.|||}
	{60|I have given Bjorgur\'s family dagger to Fulus. He thanked me for bringing it to him, and rewarded me handsomely.|170|1|}
	}|};
</string>

<string name="questlist_v0610">
[id|name|showInLog|stages[progress|logText|rewardExperience|finishesQuest|]|];
{erinith|Deep wound|1|{
	{10|Just northeast of Crossglen village, I met Erinith that has set up camp. Apparently, he was attacked during the night and lost a book.|||}
	{20|I have agreed to help Erinith find his book. He told me he threw it among some trees to the north of his camp.|||}
	{21|I have agreed to help Erinith find his book in return for 200 gold. He told me he threw it among some trees to the north of his camp.|||}
	{30|I have returned the book to Erinith.|200||}
	{31|He also needs help with his wound that doesn\'t seem to be healing. Either I should bring him one potion of major health, or four regular potions of health.|||}
	{40|I gave Erinith a bonemeal potion to heal his wound. He was a bit scared to use it since they are prohibited by Lord Geomyr.|||}
	{41|I gave Erinith a potion of a major health to heal his wound.|||}
	{42|I gave Erinith four regular potions of health to heal his wound.|||}
	{50|The wound healed completely and Erinith thanked me for all the help.|150|1|}
	}|};
{hadracor|Devastated land|1|{
	{10|On the road to Carn Tower, west of the crossroads guardhouse, I met a group of woodcutters led by Hadracor. Hadracor wants me to help him get revenge on some wasps that were attacking them while they were cutting down the forest. To help them get revenge, I should look for giant wasps near their encampment and bring him at least five giant wasp wings.|||}
	{20|I have brought five giant wasp wings to Hadracor.|||}
	{21|I have brought six giant wasp wings to Hadracor. For helping him, he gave me a pair of gloves.|||}
	{30|Hadracor thanked me for helping him and the other woodcutters get revenge on the wasps. In return, he offered me to trade for some of his items.||1|}
	}|};
{tinlyn|Lost sheep|1|{
	{10|On the road to Feygard, near the Feygard bridge, I met a shepherd named Tinlyn. Tinlyn told me that four of his sheep have wandered away and that he won\'t dare leave the remaining sheep to go look for them.|||}
	{15|I have agreed to help Tinlyn find his four lost sheep.|||}
	{20|I have found one of Tinlyn\'s lost sheep.|||}
	{21|I have found one of Tinlyn\'s lost sheep.|||}
	{22|I have found one of Tinlyn\'s lost sheep.|||}
	{23|I have found one of Tinlyn\'s lost sheep.|||}
	{25|I have found all four of Tinlyn\'s lost sheep.|||}
	{30|Tinlyn thanked me for finding his lost sheep.|350|1|}
	{31|Tinlyn thanked me for finding his lost sheep, but he had no reward to give me.|200|1|}
	{60|I have attacked at least one of Tinlyn\'s lost sheep and is therefore unable to return them all to Tinlyn.||1|}
	}|};
{benbyr|Cheap cuts|1|{
	{10|I have met Benbyr outside the Crossroads guardhouse. He wants to get revenge on an old \'business partner\' of his - Tinlyn. Benbyr wants me to kill all Tinlyn\'s sheep.|||}
	{20|I have agreed to help Benbyr find Tinlyn\'s sheep and kill all eight of them. I should go look for them in the fields northwest of the crossroads guardhouse.|||}
	{21|I have started attacking the sheep. I should return to Benbyr once I have killed all eight of them.|||}
	{30|Benbyr was thrilled to hear that all of Tinlyn\'s sheep are dead.|520|1|}
	{60|I declined to help Benbyr kill the sheep.||1|}
	}|};
{rogorn|The path is clear to me|1|{
	{10|Minarra up in the tower at the Crossroads guardhouse has seen a band of rogues heading west from the guardhouse, towards Carn Tower. Minarra was sure they matched the description of some men whose heads have a bounty on them from the Feygard patrol. If these are the men that Minarra thinks, they are supposedly led by particularly ruthless savage named Rogorn.|||}
	{20|I am helping Minarra find the band of rogues. I should travel the road west from the Crossroads guardhouse towards Carn Tower and look for them. They have supposedly stolen three pieces of a valuable painting and are wanted dead for their crimes.|||}
	{21|Minarra also tells me that I should not trust anything I hear from them. In particular, anything from Rogorn should be viewed with great suspicion.|||}
	{30|I have found the band of rogues on the road west towards Carn Tower, led by Rogorn.|||}
	{35|Rogorn tells me that they are wrongly accused of murder and theft in Feygard, while they themselves have never even been to Feygard.|||}
	{40|I have decided to attack Rogorn and his band of rogues. I should return to Minarra with the three pieces of the painting once they are dead.|||}
	{45|I have decided not to attack Rogorn and his band of rogues, but instead report back to Minarra that she must have mistaken the men she saw for someone else.|||}
	{50|Minarra thanked me for dealing with the thieves, and told me that my services to Feygard will be appreciated.|||}
	{55|After telling Minarra that she must have mistaken the men for someone else, she seemed a bit suspicious, but thanked me for helping her look into the matter.|||}
	{60|I have helped Minarra with her task.||1|}
	}|};
{feygard_shipment|Feygard errands|1|{
	{10|I met Gandoren, the guard captain at the Crossroads guardhouse. He told me about some trouble up in Loneford, that have forced the guards to be even more alert than usual. Because of this, they can\'t do their regular errands themselves but need help with some basic things.|||}
	{20|Gandoren wants me to help him transport a shipment of 10 iron swords to another guard post to the south.|||}
	{21|I have agreed to help Gandoren transport the shipment, as a service for Feygard.|||}
	{22|With some grudge, I have agreed to help Gandoren transport the shipment.|||}
	{25|I should deliver the shipment to the Feygard patrol captain stationed in the Foaming Flask tavern.|||}
	{26|Gandoren tells me that Ailshara has expressed some interest in the Feygard shipments, and urges me to stay away from her.|||}
	{30|Ailshara is indeed interested in the shipment, and wants me to help Nor City with the supplies instead.|||}
	{35|If I want to help Ailshara on behalf Nor City instead, I should deliver the shipment to the smith in Vilegard.|||}
	{50|I have delivered the shipment to the Feygard patrol captain in the Foaming Flask tavern. I should go tell Gandoren in the Crossroads guardhouse that the shipment is delivered.|||}
	{55|I have delivered the shipment to the smith in Vilegard.|||}
	{56|The Vilegard smith gave me a shipment of degraded items that I should deliver to the Feygard patrol captain in the Foaming Flask tavern instead of the normal ones.|||}
	{60|I have delivered the shipment of degraded items to the Feygard patrol captain in the Foaming Flask tavern. I should go tell Gandoren in the Crossroads guardhouse that the shipment is delivered.|||}
	{80|Gandoren thanked me for helping him deliver the shipment.|400|1|}
	{81|Gandoren thanked me for helping him deliver the shipment. He never suspected anything. I should also report back to Ailshara.|||}
	{82|I have reported back to Ailshara.|400|1|}
	}|};
{loneford|Flows through the veins|1|{
	{10|I heard a story about Loneford. Apparently, a lot of people have become ill there recently, and some have even died. The cause is still unknown.|||}
	{11|I should investigate what could have caused the people of Loneford to become ill. I should ask around people in Loneford and outside the village about clues and what people believe is the cause.|||}
	{21|The guards in the Crossroads guardhouse are certain that the illness in Loneford is caused by some sabotage done by the priests or people from Nor City.|||}
	{22|Some villagers in Loneford believe that the illness is caused by the guards from Feygard, in some scheme to make the people suffer even more than they already have.|||}
	{23|Talion, the chapel priest in Loneford, thinks that the illness is the work of the Shadow, as punishment for Loneford\'s lack of devotion to the Shadow.|||}
	{24|Taevinn in Loneford is certain that Sienn in the southeast barn has something to do with the illness. Apparently, Sienn keeps a pet around that has approached Taevinn in a threatening manner several times.|||}
	{25|I should go see Landa in the Loneford tavern. Rumor has it that he saw something that he doesn\'t dare tell anyone.|||}
	{30|Landa confused me with someone else at first. He apparently saw a small boy doing something around the town well during the night before the illness started. He was scared to talk to me at first since he though I looked like the boy he had seen. Could it have been Andor that he saw?|||}
	{31|Also, the night after he saw the boy at the well, he saw Buceth taking samples of the water in the well. Strangely enough, Buceth has not gotten ill like the others in the village.|||}
	{35|I should go question Buceth at the Loneford chapel about what he was doing at the well, and about whether he knows anything about Andor.|||}
	{41|I have bribed Buceth into talking to me.|||}
	{42|I have told Buceth that I am ready to follow the Shadow.|||}
	{45|Buceth tells me that he is assigned by the priests in Nor City to make sure the Shadow casts its glow over Loneford. Apparently, the priests had sent a boy to do some business in Loneford, and Buceth was tasked with gathering some samples from the water well.|||}
	{50|I have attacked Buceth. I should bring any evidence that Buceth has on him to Kuldan, the guard captain in the longhouse in Loneford.|||}
	{54|I have given the vial that Buceth had on him to Kuldan, the guard captain in Loneford.|||}
	{55|Kuldan thanked me for solving the mystery of the illness in Loneford. They will start bringing in water with help from Feygard instead of drinking from the well from now on. Kuldan also told me to visit the castle steward in Feygard if I want to help further.|1500|1|}
	{60|I have promised to keep Buceth\'s story a secret. If Andor was indeed here, he must have had a good reason for doing what he did. Buceth also told me to visit the chapel custodian in Nor City if I want to learn more about the Shadow.|1500|1|}
	}|};
</string>

<string name="questlist_v0611">
[id|name|showInLog|stages[progress|logText|rewardExperience|finishesQuest|]|];
{thorin|Bits and pieces|1|{
	{20|In a cave to the east, I found a man called Thorin, that wants me to help him find the remains of his former travelling companions. I should find the remains of all six of them and return them to him.|||}
	{31|I have found some skeletal remains in the same cave that I met Thorin in.|||}
	{32|I have found some skeletal remains in the same cave that I met Thorin in.|||}
	{33|I have found some skeletal remains in the same cave that I met Thorin in.|||}
	{34|I have found some skeletal remains in the same cave that I met Thorin in.|||}
	{35|I have found some skeletal remains in the same cave that I met Thorin in.|||}
	{36|I have found some skeletal remains in the same cave that I met Thorin in.|||}
	{40|Thorin thanked me for helping him. In return, he has allowed me to use his bed to rest, and is willing to sell me some of his potions.|400|1|}
	}|};
{algangror|Nothing but a squeak|1|{
	{10|In a lonely house on a peninsula at the northern shore of lake Laeroth up in the mountains to the north-east, I met Algangror. She has a rodent problem and needs help dealing with some of them that she has trapped in her basement.|||}
	{15|I have agreed to help Algangror deal with her rodent problem. I should return to her when I have killed all six rodents in her basement.|||}
	{20|Algangror thanked me for helping her with her problem.|500||}
	{21|She also told me not to talk to anyone in Remgard about her whereabouts. Apparently, they are looking for her for some reason that she would not say. Under no circumstances should I tell anyone where she is.||1|}
	}|};
{remgard|Everything in order|1|{
	{10|I have reached the bridge to enter the town of Remgard. According to the bridge guard, the town is closed for outsiders to enter, and no-one is currently allowed to leave. They are investigating some disappearances of some of the townspeople.|||}
	{15|I have offered my assistance in helping the people of Remgard investigate what has happened to the townspeople that have disappeared.|||}
	{20|The bridge guard has asked me to investigate an abandoned house to the east along the northern shore of the lake. I should be wary of any inhabitants that may be there.|||}
	{30|I have reported back to the bridge guard that I met Algangror in the abandoned house.|300||}
	{31|I have reported back to the bridge guard that the abandoned house was empty.|300||}
	{35|I have been granted entrance into Remgard. I should go visit Jhaeld, the town elder, to talk about what the next step should be. Jhaeld can probably be found in the tavern to the southeast.|||}
	}|};
</string>

</resources>
